在一个可视化布局的编辑器上构图布局是一件简单的事儿。
Building something that looks great in the visual layout editor is the easy
你同样需要考虑不同尺寸的屏幕以及画面的定位。
part. You also need to consider different screens and orientations. As you
当你开始设计你程序的UI时，
begin to layout your UI, there's a temptation to build it pixel perfect for
你得让UI的像素适合你当时使用的设备。
the device you happen to be using at the time. This is reinforced by
事实上，这是这是通过对运行程序的加强，而不是改变窗口的大小。
the fact that your apps window doesn't generally change size while it's running.
所以你不能只通过抓取低i-corner来改变界面的大小。
So you can't just grab the lower i-corner and grow and
如果你曾开发过web或者桌面应用，
shrink your app to see how it behaves. But if you've ever developed for
你就会知道设置静态方法是并不是个好办法。
the web or desktop, you know this static approach is a bad idea.
Android首次发布的标准分辨率是 480×320。
When Android first launched, HVGA 480 by 320 resolution screens were standard.
当我们开始研究如何在这些设备建立适合的用户体验时，
As we began exploring how to build engaging user experiences on those devices,
我们可以使用绝对布局来定义每个画面元件的确切位置。
we could use absolute layouts to define the exact location of each
然而不到一年的时间，宽分辨率的安卓手机就被开发出来了。
screen element. But within a year, the first WVGA Android phones were released.
现在，Android可以在任何设备上运行，从手机到平板手机到平板电脑、电视、
And now Android runs on everything from phones to phablets, tablets, TVs and
还有任意尺寸的屏幕，凡是你能想到的分辨率和宽高比都可以。
wearables with any screen size, resolution and aspect ratio you can imagine.
这，就像桌面和网页开发时你可以使用 panels 和 CSS，
So, just like desktop or web where you might use panels or
你的Android UI需要在屏幕运行的基础上进行扩展，
CSS, your Android UI needs to scale based on the screen it's running within,
这就是不使用绝对布局的原因。
which is why absolute layout was deprecated.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
支持LinearLayout布局、RelativeLayout布局、
In favor of layouts like LinearLayout, RelativeLayout and
GridLayout布局，这些能够动态调整界面，
GridLayout, they can dynamically resize and
适应任何屏幕，遵循响应式设计的原则。
adapt to any screen, following the principles of responsive design.